<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<catalog>
    <author>
        <total_citations>107</total_citations>
        <list_years>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2016</year_date>
                <year_count>1</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2015</year_date>
                <year_count>30</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2014</year_date>
                <year_count>18</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2013</year_date>
                <year_count>22</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2012</year_date>
                <year_count>15</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2011</year_date>
                <year_count>7</year_count>
            </year_citation>
            <year_citation>
                <year_date>2010</year_date>
                <year_count>3</year_count>
            </year_citation>
        </list_years>
        <publications>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Javier Cámara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, Marco Vieira
                </pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2015/5/4</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>-</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>-</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—An increasingly important requirement for certain classes of
                    software-intensive systems is the ability to self-adapt their structure and behavior at run-time
                    when reacting to changes that may occur to the system, its environment, or its goals. A major
                    challenge related to self-adaptive software systems is the ability to provide assurances of their
                    resilience when facing changes. Since in these systems, the components that act as controllers of a
                    target system incorporate highly complex software, there is the need to ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems J
                    Cámara, R de Lemos, N Laranjeiro, R Ventura… - 2015 Cited by 1 - Related articles - All 8 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>1</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Quinn, Heather, Zachary Baker, Tom Fairbanks, Justin L. Tripp, and George Duran.
                            "Software Resilience and the Effectiveness of Software Mitigation in Microcontrollers."
                            Nuclear Science, IEEE Transactions on 62, no. 6 (2015): 2532-2538.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Characterizing the performance of web service frameworks under security attacks</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Rui André Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2015/4/13</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Proceedings of the 30th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>1711-1718</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>ACM</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract Web Services are a platform-independent technology that enables business
                    processes to be accessible worldwide. In this context, web service frameworks play a key role as
                    intermediate layers, offering support for interoperability and communication between providers and
                    consumers. Due to their relevance in the overall infrastructure, frameworks are a frequent target of
                    attacks trying to impact the performance of the provided services. This paper proposes an
                    experimental approach for assessing the performance of web ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Characterizing the performance of web service frameworks under security attacks RA
                    Oliveira, N Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Proceedings of the 30th Annual ACM Symposium on …, 2015 Cited by
                    1 - Related articles
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>1</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bulusu, Pranahita. "Detection of Lightweight Directory Access Protocol Query Injection
                            Attacks in Web Applications." (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Understanding Interoperability Issues of Web Service Frameworks</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Ivano Alessandro Elia, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2014/6/23</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Dependable Systems and Networks (DSN), 2014 44th Annual IEEE/IFIP International
                    Conference on
                </pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>323-330</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Web Services are a set of technologies designed to support the invocation of
                    remote services by client applications, with the key goal of providing interoperable
                    application-to-application interaction while supporting vendor and platform independence. The goal
                    of this work is to study the real level of interoperability provided by these technologies through a
                    massive experimental campaign involving a wide set of very popular frameworks for web services,
                    implemented using seven different programming languages. ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Understanding Interoperability Issues of Web Service Frameworks IA Elia, N
                    Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Dependable Systems and Networks (DSN), 2014 44th …, 2014 Cited by 3 - Related
                    articles - All 4 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>3</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "A Practical Approach
                            Towards Automatic Testing of Web Services Interoperability." International Journal of Web
                            Services Research (IJWSR) 12, no. 3 (2015): 78-103.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "A Field Perspective on the
                            Interoperability of Web Services." In Services Computing (SCC), 2014 IEEE International
                            Conference on, pp. 75-82. IEEE, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Elia, Ivano Alessandro, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "ITWS: An Extensible Tool
                            for Interoperability Testing of Web Services." In Web Services (ICWS), 2014 IEEE
                            International Conference on, pp. 409-416. IEEE, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Testing the robustness of controllers for self-adaptive systems</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Javier Cámara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, Marco Vieira
                </pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2014/1/23</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>-</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>Journal of the Brazilian Computer Society</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>20</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>1</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>1</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>Springer London</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract Self-adaptive systems are software-intensive systems endowed with the ability
                    to respond to a variety of changes that may occur in their environment, goals, or the system itself
                    by adapting their structure and behaviour at run-time in an autonomous way. Controllers are complex
                    components incorporated in self-adaptive systems, which are crucial to their function since they are
                    in charge of adapting the target system by executing actions through effectors, based on information
                    monitored by probes. However, although ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Testing the robustness of controllers for self-adaptive systems J Cámara, R de
                    Lemos, N Laranjeiro, R Ventura… - Journal of the Brazilian Computer Society, 2014 Cited by 6 -
                    Related articles - All 9 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>6</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Fredericks, Erik M., and Betty HC Cheng. "Automated generation of adaptive test plans
                            for self-adaptive systems." In Proceedings of the 10th International Symposium on Software
                            Engineering for Adaptive and Self-Managing Systems, pp. 157-168. IEEE Press, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Abuseta, Yousef, and Khaled Swesi. "Design Patterns for Self Adaptive Systems
                            Engineering." arXiv preprint arXiv:1508.01330 (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Hansel, Joachim, Thomas Vogel, and Holger Giese. "A Testing Scheme for Self-Adaptive
                            Software Systems with Architectural Runtime Models." In Self-Adaptive and Self-Organizing
                            Systems Workshops (SASOW), 2015 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 134-139. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Abuseta, Yousef, and Khaled Swesi. "Towards a framework for testing and simulating
                            self adaptive systems." In Software Engineering and Service Science (ICSESS), 2015 6th IEEE
                            International Conference on, pp. 70-76. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Weyns, Danny, Nelly Bencomo, Radu Calinescu, Javier Camara, Carlo Ghezzi, Vincenzo
                            Grassi, Lars Grunske et al. "Perpetual assurances in self-adaptive systems." In Assurances
                            for Self-Adaptive Systems, Dagstuhl Seminar, vol. 13511. 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Gil de La Iglesia, Didac. "A Formal Approach for Designing Distributed Self-Adaptive
                            Systems." (2014).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>A technique for deploying robust web services</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2014/1</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>-</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>Services Computing, IEEE Transactions on</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>7</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>1</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>68-81</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Developing robust web services is a difficult task. Field studies show that a
                    large number of web services are deployed with robustness problems (ie, presenting unexpected
                    behaviors in the presence of invalid inputs). Although several techniques for the identification of
                    robustness problems have been proposed in the past, there is no practical approach to automatically
                    fix those problems. This paper proposes a mechanism that automatically fixes robustness problems in
                    web services. The approach consists of using ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>A technique for deploying robust web services N Laranjeiro, M Vieira, H Madeira -
                    Services Computing, IEEE Transactions on, 2014 Cited by 7 - Related articles - All 7 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>7</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Natella, Roberto, Domenico Cotroneo, and Henrique S. Madeira. "Assessing Dependability
                            with Software Fault Injection: A Survey." ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR) 48, no. 3 (2016): 44.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2016</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Quinn, Heather, and Michael Wirthlin. "Validation Techniques for Fault Emulation of
                            SRAM-based FPGAs." Nuclear Science, IEEE Transactions on 62, no. 4 (2015): 1487-1500.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Thome, Julian, Lwin Khin Shar, and Lionel Briand. "Security slicing for auditing XML,
                            XPath, and SQL injection vulnerabilities." In Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE), 2015
                            IEEE 26th International Symposium on, pp. 553-564. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Devi, V., and R. Kanagaselvi. "ENDORSE THE TRUSTFUL QoS TO CRAFT MASHUP/BUSINESS
                            ORIENTED WEB SERVICES AND RECTIFY MALICIOUS ATTACKS." (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Lanzaro, Anna, Roberto Natella, Stefan Winter, Domenico Cotroneo, and Neeraj Suri. "An
                            empirical study of injected versus actual interface errors." In Proceedings of the 2014
                            International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, pp. 397-408. ACM, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Cotroneo, Domenico, and Roberto Natella. "Towards Patching Memory Leak Bugs in
                            Off-The-Shelf Software." In Software Reliability Engineering Workshops (ISSREW), 2014 IEEE
                            International Symposium on, pp. 433-436. IEEE, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Wu, Yiqi, Fazhi He, Dejun Zhang, and Xiaoxia Li. "Service-Oriented Feature-Based Data
                            Exchange for Cloud-Based Design and Manufacturing."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Towards evaluating the impact of data quality on service applications</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Naghmeh Ivaki, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2013/6/24</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Dependable Systems and Networks Workshop (DSN-W), 2013 43rd Annual IEEE/IFIP Conference
                    on
                </pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>1-7</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Service applications frequently make use of a relational database to store and
                    retrieve data and rely on the correctness of this data to deliver service to clients. Despite this,
                    relational databases do not provide support for complex data integrity restrictions, which have to
                    be controlled by the application. As such, bugs present in service applications can easily lead to
                    the storage of incorrect data that, at random instants can cause applications to fail and stop
                    delivering service, which can severely impact clients, other applications, and ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Towards evaluating the impact of data quality on service applications N Ivaki, N
                    Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Dependable Systems and Networks Workshop (DSN- …, 2013 Cited by 1 - Related
                    articles - All 4 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>1</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Laranjeiro, Nuno, Seyma Nur Soydemir, and Jorge Bernardino. "A Survey on Data Quality:
                            Classifying Poor Data." In Dependable Computing (PRDC), 2015 IEEE 21st Pacific Rim
                            International Symposium on, pp. 179-188. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Robustness evaluation of controllers in self-adaptive software systems</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Javier Camara, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Renato Ventura, Marco Vieira
                </pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2013/4/1</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Dependable Computing (LADC), 2013 Sixth Latin-American Symposium on</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>1-10</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract An increasingly important requirement for softwareintensive systems is the
                    ability to self-manage by adapting their structure and behavior at run-time in an autonomous way as
                    a response to a variety of changes that may occur to the system, its environment, or its goals. In
                    particular, self-adaptive (or autonomic) systems incorporate complex software components that act as
                    controllers of a target system by executing actions through effectors, based on information
                    monitored by probes. However, although these controllers are ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Robustness evaluation of controllers in self-adaptive software systems J Camara, R
                    de Lemos, N Laranjeiro, R Ventura… - Dependable Computing (LADC), 2013 Sixth Latin- …, 2013 Cited by
                    7 - Related articles - All 9 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>7</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Cámara, Javier, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, and Marco Vieira.
                            "Robustness-Driven Resilience Evaluation of Self-Adaptive Software Systems." (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Robert, Max, Yu Sun, Thomas Goodwin, Hamilton Turner, Jeffrey H. Reed, and Jules
                            White. "Software Frameworks for SDR." Proceedings of the IEEE 103, no. 3 (2015): 452-475.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Cámara, Javier, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, and Marco Vieira.
                            "Testing the robustness of controllers for self-adaptive systems." Journal of the Brazilian
                            Computer Society 20, no. 1 (2014): 1.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Cámara, Javier, Pedro Correia, Rogério de Lemos, and Marco Vieira. "Empirical
                            resilience evaluation of an architecture-based self-adaptive software system." In
                            Proceedings of the 10th international ACM Sigsoft conference on Quality of software
                            architectures, pp. 63-72. ACM, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Cámara, Javier, Rogério de Lemos, Nuno Laranjeiro, Rafael Ventura, and Marco Vieira.
                            "Robustness evaluation of the rainbow framework for self-adaptation." In Proceedings of the
                            29th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing, pp. 376-383. ACM, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Rotondi Azevedo, Denise, Ana Maria Ambrosio, and Marco Vieira. "HLA Middleware
                            Robustness and Scalability Evaluation in the Context of Satellite Simulators." In Dependable
                            Computing (PRDC), 2013 IEEE 19th Pacific Rim International Symposium on, pp. 312-317. IEEE,
                            2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>da Silva, Carlos Eduardo. "5.34 Runtime Testing of Self-Adaptive Systems." Software
                            Engineering for Self-Adaptive Systems: Assurances: 94.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>WSFAggressor: an extensible web service framework attacking tool</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Rui André Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2012/12/6</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Proceedings of the Industrial Track of the 13th ACM/IFIP/USENIX International Middleware
                    Conference
                </pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>2</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>ACM</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract This paper presents a tool for testing the security of web service frameworks.
                    The tool implements a large set of attack types, defined based on previous security research
                    studies, existing testing tools, and field experience. The motivation is that developers frequently
                    build web services based on the assumption that the underlying frameworks are secure, which is not
                    always the case. Despite the evident need for security in the platforms that support services,
                    existing security testing tools are very limited. In practice, most tools ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>WSFAggressor: an extensible web service framework attacking tool RA Oliveira, N
                    Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Proceedings of the Industrial Track of the 13th ACM/ …, 2012 Cited by 4 -
                    Related articles - All 2 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>4</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Characterizing the
                            performance of web service frameworks under security attacks." In Proceedings of the 30th
                            Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing, pp. 1711-1718. ACM, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Jan, Sadeeq, Cu D. Nguyen, and Lionel Briand. "Known XML Vulnerabilities Are Still a
                            Threat to Popular Parsers and Open Source Systems." In Software Quality, Reliability and
                            Security (QRS), 2015 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 233-241. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Assessing the security of web
                            service frameworks against Denial of Service attacks." Journal of Systems and Software 109
                            (2015): 18-31.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Stage, Ludwig. "Entwurf einer Methodik zum Testen der Sicherheit von
                            Web-Service-basierten Systemen." (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>A robustness testing approach for SOAP Web services</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2012/9/1</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>-</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>Journal of Internet Services and Applications</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>3</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>2</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>215-232</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>Springer-Verlag</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract The use of Web services in enterprise applications is quickly increasing. In a
                    Web services environment, providers supply a set of services for consumers. However, although Web
                    services are being used in business-critical environments, there are no practical means to test or
                    compare their robustness to invalid and malicious inputs. In fact, client applications are typically
                    developed with the assumption that the services being used are robust, which is not always the case.
                    Robustness failures in such environments are particularly dangerous ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>A robustness testing approach for SOAP Web services N Laranjeiro, M Vieira, H
                    Madeira - Journal of Internet Services and Applications, 2012 Cited by 3 - Related articles - All 5
                    versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>3</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Besson, Felipe, Paulo Moura, Fabio Kon, and Dejan Milojicic. "Bringing Test-Driven
                            Development to web service choreographies." Journal of Systems and Software 99 (2015):
                            135-154.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Hourani, Mou'ath, Qusai Shambour, Ahmad Al-Zubidy, and Ali Al-Smadi. "Proposed design
                            and implementation for RESTful web server." Journal of Software 9, no. 5 (2014): 1071-1080.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Ivaki, Naghmeh, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Towards evaluating the impact of
                            data quality on service applications." In Dependable Systems and Networks Workshop (DSN-W),
                            2013 43rd Annual IEEE/IFIP Conference on, pp. 1-7. IEEE, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Experimental evaluation of web service frameworks in the presence of security attacks
                </pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Rui Andre Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2012/6/24</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Services Computing (SCC), 2012 IEEE Ninth International Conference on</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>633-640</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Web services are increasingly being used to provide critical operations in
                    business-to-business and safety-critical environments. In these environments the exploitation of
                    security vulnerabilities may result in major damages in the services infrastructures, financial or
                    reputation losses to the organizations involved, and other catastrophic consequences for the users
                    and the environment. Web services frameworks are the basis for developers to create and deploy web
                    services, and must provide a robust ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Experimental evaluation of web service frameworks in the presence of security
                    attacks RA Oliveira, N Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Services Computing (SCC), 2012 IEEE Ninth …, 2012
                    Cited by 7 - Related articles - All 4 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>7</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Characterizing the
                            performance of web service frameworks under security attacks." In Proceedings of the 30th
                            Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing, pp. 1711-1718. ACM, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Assessing the security of web
                            service frameworks against Denial of Service attacks." Journal of Systems and Software 109
                            (2015): 18-31.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Falkenberg, Andreas, Christian Mainka, Juraj Somorovsky, and Jörg Schwenk. "A new
                            approach towards DoS penetration testing on web services." In Web Services (ICWS), 2013 IEEE
                            20th International Conference on, pp. 491-498. IEEE, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Stage, Ludwig. "Entwurf einer Methodik zum Testen der Sicherheit von
                            Web-Service-basierten Systemen." (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "WSFAggressor: an extensible
                            web service framework attacking tool." In Proceedings of the Industrial Track of the 13th
                            ACM/IFIP/USENIX International Middleware Conference, p. 2. ACM, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bhandari, Lekha V., and Avinash P. Wadhe. "Enhancing Security Performance of SOAP in
                            web services using RSA algorithm."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Datir, Ankita A., and Amit Sahu. "A Review on Enhancing Privacy Preservation of Web
                            Service through Negotiation Mechanism."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>A Composed Approach for Automatic Classification of Web Services Robustness</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Rui Oliveira, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2011/7/4</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Services Computing (SCC), 2011 IEEE International Conference on</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>176-183</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Testing Web Services (WS) for robustness is a lengthy and arduous process.
                    After testing a set of services, there is typically a very large quantity and variety of test
                    results to be analyzed, which poses a challenge to the developer that has to manually process all
                    results and identify the outputs that indicate the presence of bugs in the code. Previous research
                    indicates that well-known automatic classification algorithms can be used to automate this step.
                    However, the applicability of such algorithms is also limited, as they are frequently ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>A Composed Approach for Automatic Classification of Web Services Robustness R
                    Oliveira, N Laranjeiro, M Vieira - Services Computing (SCC), 2011 IEEE International …, 2011 Cited
                    by 2 - Related articles - All 6 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>2</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Syed Mustafa, A., and Kumara Swamy. "Web Service classification using Multi-Layer
                            Perceptron optimized with Tabu search." In Advance Computing Conference (IACC), 2015 IEEE
                            International, pp. 290-294. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bozkurt, Mustafa. "Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in
                            Service-centric System Testing." PhD diss., UCL (University College London), 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>WSRTesting: Hands-on Solution to Improve Web Services Robustness Testing</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>G Carrozza, A Napolitano, N Laranjeiro, M Viera</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2011/4/25</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Dependable Computing Workshops (LADCW), 2011 Fifth Latin-American Symposium on
                </pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>41-46</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract-Web services are widely used as software components that must provide a robust
                    interface to client applications. Robustness testing is an approach particularly suitable for
                    detecting robustness issues in web services. In fact, several research works have been conducted in
                    the past leading to the proposal of different robustness testing techniques for such environments.
                    However, although of utmost importance, most techniques do not consider the needs of complex systems
                    and services as the ones being developed by the ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>WSRTesting: Hands-on Solution to Improve Web Services Robustness Testing G
                    Carrozza, A Napolitano, N Laranjeiro, M Viera - … Computing Workshops (LADCW), 2011 Fifth Latin- …,
                    2011 Cited by 1 - Related articles - All 7 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>1</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bozkurt, Mustafa. "Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in
                            Service-centric System Testing." PhD diss., UCL (University College London), 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>A Learning-Based Approach to Secure Web Services from SQL/XPath Injection Attacks</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2010/12/13</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Dependable Computing (PRDC), 2010 IEEE 16th Pacific Rim International Symposium on
                </pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>191-198</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Business critical applications are increasingly being deployed as web services
                    that access database systems, and must provide secure operations to its clients. Although the open
                    web environment emphasizes the need for security, several studies show that web services are still
                    being deployed with command injection vulnerabilities. This paper proposes a learning-based approach
                    to secure web services against SQL and XPath Injection attacks. Our approach is able to
                    transparently learn valid request patterns ( ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>A Learning-Based Approach to Secure Web Services from SQL/XPath Injection Attacks
                    N Laranjeiro, M Vieira, H Madeira - Dependable Computing (PRDC), 2010 IEEE 16th …, 2010 Cited by 2 -
                    Related articles - All 6 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>2</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Silva, Carlo Marcelo Revoredo da. "Aegis: Um Modelo de Proteção à Dados Sensíveis em
                            Ambientes Client-side." (2014).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Gupta, Abhinav Nath, and P. Santhi Thilagam. "Attacks on Web Services Need to Secure
                            XML on Web." Computer Science &amp; Engineering 3, no. 5 (2013): 1.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Applying Text Classification Algorithms in Web Services Robustness Testing</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Nuno Laranjeiro, Rui Oliveira, Marco Vieira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2010/10/31</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Reliable Distributed Systems, 2010 29th IEEE Symposium on</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>255-264</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract—Testing web services for robustness is an effective way of disclosing software
                    bugs. However, when executing robustness tests, a very large amount of service responses has to be
                    manually classified to distinguish regular responses from responses that indicate robustness
                    problems. Besides requiring a large amount of time and effort, this complex classification process
                    can easily lead to errors resulting from the human intervention in such a laborious task. Text
                    classification algorithms have been applied successfully in many ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Applying text classification algorithms in web services robustness testing N
                    Laranjeiro, R Oliveira, M Vieira - Reliable Distributed Systems, 2010 29th IEEE …, 2010 Cited by 11
                    - Related articles - All 6 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>11</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Laranjeiro, Nuno, Marco Vieira, and Henrique Madeira. "A technique for deploying
                            robust web services." Services Computing, IEEE Transactions on 7, no. 1 (2014): 68-81.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Mustafa, A. Syed, and Y. S. Kumaraswamy. "Data mining algorithms for Web-services
                            classification." In Contemporary Computing and Informatics (IC3I), 2014 International
                            Conference on, pp. 951-956. IEEE, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bozkurt, Mustafa, Mark Harman, and Youssef Hassoun. "Testing and verification in
                            service‐oriented architecture: a survey." Software Testing, Verification and Reliability 23,
                            no. 4 (2013): 261-313.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shahrokni, Ali, and Robert Feldt. "A systematic review of software robustness."
                            Information and Software Technology 55, no. 1 (2013): 1-17.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Di Leo, Domenico. "Robustness Evaluation of Software Systems through Fault Injection."
                            (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bozkurt, Mustafa. "Automated Realistic Test Input Generation and Cost Reduction in
                            Service-centric System Testing." PhD diss., UCL (University College London), 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Laranjeiro, Nuno, Marco Vieira, and Henrique Madeira. "A robustness testing approach
                            for SOAP Web services." Journal of Internet Services and Applications 3, no. 2 (2012):
                            215-232.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Lemos, Gizelle Sandrini, and Eliane Martins. "Specification-guided golden run for
                            analysis of robustness testing results." In Software Security and Reliability (SERE), 2012
                            IEEE Sixth International Conference on, pp. 157-166. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Hongjian, Guo, and Chen Yifei. "Web Classification Algorithm Using Support Vector
                            Machine and Particle Swarm Optimization." International Journal of Advancements in Computing
                            Technology 4, no. 17 (2012).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "A Composed Approach for Automatic
                            Classification of Web Services Robustness." In Services Computing (SCC), 2011 IEEE
                            International Conference on, pp. 176-183. IEEE, 2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Ma, Ying, Fei Wang, and Jian Wu. "Locality Sensitive Hashing Based Service
                            Classification." In Management and Service Science (MASS), 2011 International Conference on,
                            pp. 1-5. IEEE, 2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
            <publication>
                <pub_title>Effective Detection of SQL/XPath Injection Vulnerabilities in Web Services</pub_title>
                <pub_authors>Nuno Antunes, Nuno Laranjeiro, Marco Vieira, Henrique Madeira</pub_authors>
                <pub_date>2009/9/21</pub_date>
                <pub_conference>Services Computing, 2009. SCC'09. IEEE International Conference on</pub_conference>
                <pub_journal>-</pub_journal>
                <pub_volume>-</pub_volume>
                <pub_issue>-</pub_issue>
                <pub_pages>260-267</pub_pages>
                <pub_publisher>IEEE</pub_publisher>
                <pub_description>Abstract This paper proposes a new automatic approach for the detection of SQL
                    Injection and XPath Injection vulnerabilities, two of the most dao and most critical types of
                    vulnerabilities in web services. Although there are tools that allow testing web applications
                    against security vulnerabilities, previous research shows that the effectiveness of those tools in
                    web services environments is very poor. In our approach a representative workload is used to
                    exercise the web service and a large set of SQL/XPath Injection attacks are ...
                </pub_description>
                <pub_scholar_articles>Effective detection of SQL/XPath injection vulnerabilities in web services N
                    Antunes, N Laranjeiro, M Vieira, H Madeira - Services Computing, 2009. SCC'09. IEEE International …,
                    2009 Cited by 51 - Related articles - All 6 versions
                </pub_scholar_articles>
                <n_citations>51</n_citations>
                <list_citations>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Assessing and Comparing Vulnerability Detection
                            Tools for Web Services: Benchmarking Approach and Examples." Services Computing, IEEE
                            Transactions on 8, no. 2 (2015): 269-283.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Appelt, Dennis, Cu D. Nguyen, and Lionel Briand. "Behind an Application Firewall, Are
                            We Safe from SQL Injection Attacks?." In Software Testing, Verification and Validation
                            (ICST), 2015 IEEE 8th International Conference on, pp. 1-10. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Mehta, Punit, Jigar Sharda, and Manik Lal Das. "SQLshield: Preventing SQL Injection
                            Attacks by Modifying User Input Data." In Information Systems Security, pp. 192-206.
                            Springer International Publishing, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>韩明, and 苗长云. "Structured Query Language Injection Penetration Test Case Generation
                            Based on Formal Description." 东华大学学报: 英文版 32, no. 3 (2015): 446-452.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Chandrasekar, A. "A web services access control model based on multifactor trust
                            authorization policy." (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shirani, Paria, Mohammad Abdollahi Azgomi, and Saed Alrabaee. "A method for intrusion
                            detection in web services based on time series." In Electrical and Computer Engineering
                            (CCECE), 2015 IEEE 28th Canadian Conference on, pp. 836-841. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>AR, Mohamed Shanavas. "Identifying SOA Security Threats using Web Mining."
                            International Journal of Computer Applications 120, no. 4 (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Assessing the security of web
                            service frameworks against Denial of Service attacks." Journal of Systems and Software 109
                            (2015): 18-31.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "On the Metrics for Benchmarking Vulnerability
                            Detection Tools." In Dependable Systems and Networks (DSN), 2015 45th Annual IEEE/IFIP
                            International Conference on, pp. 505-516. IEEE, 2015.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>ชาตรี ทอง วรรณ, and วร พล ลีลา เกียรติ สกุล. "กรอบ การ ทำงาน ใหม่ ใน การ ป้องกัน การ
                            โจม &amp;# 3605..." Journal of Information Science &amp; Technology 5, no. 1 (2015).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2015</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Appelt, Dennis, Cu Duy Nguyen, Lionel C. Briand, and Nadia Alshahwan. "Automated
                            testing for SQL injection vulnerabilities: an input mutation approach." In Proceedings of
                            the 2014 International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, pp. 259-269. ACM, 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Appelt, Dennis, Nadia Alshahwan, Duy Cu Nguyen, and Lionel Briand. Black-box sql
                            injection testing. No. TR-SnT-2014-1. 2014.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Ghourabi, Abdallah, Tarek Abbes, and Adel Bouhoula. "Characterization of attacks
                            collected from the deployment of Web service honeypot." Security and Communication Networks
                            7, no. 2 (2014): 338-351.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Mirjalili, Mahin, Alireza Nowroozi, and Mitra Alidoosti. "A survey on web penetration
                            test." (2014).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Saha, Tushar Kanti, and ABM Shawkat Ali. "Web Application Security Attacks and
                            Countermeasures." Case Studies in Secure Computing: Achievements and Trends (2014): 343.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2014</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Soa-scanner: An integrated tool to detect
                            vulnerabilities in service-based infrastructures." In Services Computing (SCC), 2013 IEEE
                            International Conference on, pp. 280-287. IEEE, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Gupta, Abhinav Nath, and P. Santhi Thilagam. "Attacks on Web Services Need to Secure
                            XML on Web." Computer Science &amp; Engineering 3, no. 5 (2013): 1.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Security Testing in SOAs: Techniques and Tools." In
                            Innovative Technologies for Dependable OTS-Based Critical Systems, pp. 159-174. Springer
                            Milan, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shafie, Emad. "Runtime Detection and Prevention for Structure Query Language Injection
                            Attacks." (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Lei, Liu, Xu Jing, Li Minglei, and Yang Jufeng. "A Dynamic SQL injection vulnerability
                            test case generation model based on the multiple phases detection approach." In Computer
                            Software and Applications Conference (COMPSAC), 2013 IEEE 37th Annual, pp. 256-261. IEEE,
                            2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Phocharoen, Wanwisa, and Twittie Senivongse. "A Security Attack Risk Assessment for
                            Web Services Based on Data Schemas and Semantics." In Proceedings of the 2012 International
                            Conference on Information Technology and Software Engineering, pp. 135-143. Springer Berlin
                            Heidelberg, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Zech, Philipp, Michael Felderer, Matthias Farwick, and Ruth Breu. "A Concept for
                            Language-Oriented Security Testing." In Software Security and Reliability-Companion
                            (SERE-C), 2013 IEEE 7th International Conference on, pp. 53-62. IEEE, 2013.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Asmawi, Aziah, Lilly Suriani Affendey, Nur Izura Udzir, and Ramlan Mahmod. "XIPS: a
                            model-based prevention mechanism for preventing blind XPath injection in database-centric
                            web services environment." International Journal of Advancements in Computing Technology 5,
                            no. 10 (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>罗启汉, 张玉清, and 刘奇旭. "针对 RESTful API 的 SQL 注入漏洞检测工具的设计与实现." 中国科学院大学学报 30, no. 3 (2013):
                            417-424.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Stage, Ludwig. "Entwurf einer Methodik zum Testen der Sicherheit von
                            Web-Service-basierten Systemen." (2013).
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2013</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui Andre, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "Experimental evaluation of
                            web service frameworks in the presence of security attacks." In Services Computing (SCC),
                            2012 IEEE Ninth International Conference on, pp. 633-640. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Wei, Tian, Yang Ju-Feng, Xu Jing, and Si Guan-Nan. "Attack model based penetration
                            test for SQL injection vulnerability." In Computer Software and Applications Conference
                            Workshops (COMPSACW), 2012 IEEE 36th Annual, pp. 589-594. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Evaluating and improving penetration testing in web
                            services." In Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE), 2012 IEEE 23rd International
                            Symposium on, pp. 201-210. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "WSFAggressor: an extensible
                            web service framework attacking tool." In Proceedings of the Industrial Track of the 13th
                            ACM/IFIP/USENIX International Middleware Conference, p. 2. ACM, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Asmawi, Aziah, Lilly Suriani Affendey, Nur Izura Udzir, and Ramlan Mahmod.
                            "Model-based system architecture for preventing XPath injection in database-centric web
                            services environment." In Computing and Convergence Technology (ICCCT), 2012 7th
                            International Conference on, pp. 621-625. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shanmughaneethi, V., Ra Yagna Praveen, and S. Swamynathan. "CIVD: detection of command
                            injection vulnerabilities in web services through aspect–oriented programming."
                            International Journal of Computer Applications in Technology 44, no. 4 (2012): 312-320.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Bondavalli, Andrea, Henrique Madeira, and Paolo Lollini. "Future of Resilience
                            Assessment: The AMBER Research Roadmap." In Resilience Assessment and Evaluation of
                            Computing Systems, pp. 415-439. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Zhang, Zong Zhi, Qiao Yan Wen, and Zhao Zhang. "An Improved Approach for SQL Injection
                            Vulnerabilities Detection." In Applied Mechanics and Materials, vol. 263, pp. 3017-3020.
                            Trans Tech Publications, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Detecting Vulnerabilities in Service Oriented
                            Architectures." In Software Reliability Engineering Workshops (ISSREW), 2012 IEEE 23rd
                            International Symposium on, pp. 134-139. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Liu, Kaiping, Hee Beng Kuan Tan, and Lwin Khin Shar. "Semi-Automated Verification of
                            Defense against SQL Injection in Web Applications." In Software Engineering Conference
                            (APSEC), 2012 19th Asia-Pacific, vol. 1, pp. 91-96. IEEE, 2012.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>田伟, 许静, 杨巨峰, 张莹, and 刘磊. "模型驱动的 Web 应用 SQL 注入渗透测试." 高技术通讯 22, no. 11 (2012):
                            1161-1168.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2012</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Enhancing penetration testing with attack signatures
                            and interface monitoring for the detection of injection vulnerabilities in web services." In
                            Services Computing (SCC), 2011 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 104-111. IEEE, 2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>van der Loo, Frank. "Comparison of penetration testing tools for web applications."
                            PhD diss., Master thesis, Radboud University Nijmegen, 2011. http://www. ru.
                            nl/publish/pages/578936/frank_van_der_loo_scriptie. pdf, 2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shanmughaneethi, Velu, Ra Yagna Pravin, and S. Swamynathan. "XIVD: Runtime Detection
                            of XPath Injection Vulnerabilities in XML Databases through Aspect Oriented Programming." In
                            Advances in Computing and Information Technology, pp. 192-201. Springer Berlin Heidelberg,
                            2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Shanmughaneethi, V., R. Ravichandran, and S. Swamynathan. "PXpathV: Preventing XPath
                            Injection Vulnerabilities in Web Applications." International Journal on Web Service
                            Computing 2, no. 3 (2011): 57.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Pais, Alwyn Roshan, D. J. Deepak, and B. R. Chandavarkar. "Protection against Denial
                            of Service and Input Manipulation Vulnerabilities in Service Oriented Architecture." In
                            Advances in Network Security and Applications, pp. 331-343. Springer Berlin Heidelberg,
                            2011.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2011</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno, and Marco Vieira. "Benchmarking vulnerability detection tools for web
                            services." In Web Services (ICWS), 2010 IEEE International Conference on, pp. 203-210. IEEE,
                            2010.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2010</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Madan, Sushila. "Security Standards Perspective to Fortify Web Database Applications
                            From Code Injection Attacks." In Intelligent Systems, Modelling and Simulation (ISMS), 2010
                            International Conference on, pp. 226-230. IEEE, 2010.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2010</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Anchlia, Ankit, and Sheela Jain. "A Novel Injection Aware Approach for the Testing of
                            Database Applications." In Recent Trends in Information, Telecommunication and Computing
                            (ITC), 2010 International Conference on, pp. 311-313. IEEE, 2010.
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>2010</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Manoj, R. Joseph, A. Chandrasekhar, and MD Anto Praveena. "An Approach to Detect and
                            Prevent Tautology Type SQL Injection in Web Service Based on XSchema validation."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Mohamed Ibrahim, B., and A. R. Mohamed Shanavas. "Severe SOA Security Threats on SOAP
                            Web Services–A Critical Analysis."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Lundgren, Ib. "Securing public APIs using OAuth and OAuthLib."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Oliveira, Rui André, Nuno Laranjeiro, and Marco Vieira. "WSFAgressor: An Extensible
                            Web Service Framework Attacker Tool."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Antunes, Nuno. "Methodologies and tools for the development of non-vulnerable Web
                            Services."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>dos Santos Antunes, Nuno Manuel. "Department of Informatics Engineering Faculty of
                            Science and Technology."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                    <citation>
                        <cit_text>Moraes, Regina, and Nuno Antunes UC. "MSc Proposal: Code coverage analysis to improve
                            vulnerability detection tests."
                        </cit_text>
                        <cit_date>1900</cit_date>
                    </citation>
                </list_citations>
            </publication>
        </publications>
    </author>
</catalog>
